Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall Collection; ead apap067
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall Collection
1979-1985
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall (Guilderland, N.Y.).
apap067
5.33 cubic ft. 3 Digital Files
Materials relating to the application of the Pyramid Crossgates Company to the New York State DEC and DOT for permits to build the Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall in the Albany Pine Bush.
Historical Note
First proposed in 1978, the Crossgates Mall is a shopping mall located in the Albany suburb of Guilderland, New York, near or in the Albany Pine Push area. The mall opened on March 4, 1984, and in October 1994 underwent a large expansion that nearly doubled its size. An additional 1998 expansion was dropped due to environmental concerns.
Scope and Contents
This Collection consists of materials relating to the application of the Pyramid Crossgates Company to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation and Department of Transportation for permits to build the Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall in the Albany Pine Bush.
The Collection begins with a 1979 report on a review of archaeological and historical literature. The most extensive of the studies and reports is the draft environmental impact statement with its fourteen appendices. The applications, responses, and decisions are of importance. The Stenographic Record on the hearings provide information on the legal developments. Historical maps are included, together with maps and photographs of the actual area or of models. Clippings from newspapers and periodicals have been added to the collection for the convenience of researchers and to bring information in the collection up to 1984 when the shopping mall opened.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arrangement within the two series is chronological except for the maps (arranged by topics) and the photographs (arranged as labeled).
Acquisition Information
Except for the clippings, all of the items in the Collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, as one of the six locations where these documents were available for public inspection at the time of the hearings.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
City planning -- New York (State) -- Guilderland (Town).; Zoning law -- New York (State) -- Guilderland (Town).; Environmental protection -- New York (State) -- Citizen participation.; Shopping malls -- New York (State).; Architecture; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Albany, New York; Conservation and the Environment; Digital Files; New York (State). Department of Environmental Conservation; New York (State). Department of Transportation; Crossgates Regional Shopping Mall (Guilderland, N.Y.); Pyramid Company.
- Printed Material, 1979-1985; 1; 1 cubic ft. 3 Digital Files
  Scope and Contents
  The series includes draft environmental impact statements, responses and decisions. Maps and photographs of the actual area and of models are also included. Clippings are from newspapers and periodicals and deal with the application, the Albany Pine Bush, and the opening of the shopping mall.
  - Literature Review, 1979 March (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 1)
  - Archaeological Field Survey, 1979 May (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 2)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement, 1979 May 31 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 3)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - letter, 1970 November 16-30 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 4)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix A. Permit Applications and Environmental Assessment Form, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 5)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix B. Market Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 6)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix circa Traffic Impact Study, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 7)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix D. Alternative Site Analysis, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 8)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix E. Vegetation and Wildlife Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 9)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix. F. Soils. Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 10)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix G. Water Resources Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 11)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix H. Air Resources Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 12)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix I. Econometric Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 13)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix J. Socioeconomic Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 14)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement - Appendix K. Fiscal Impact Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 15)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement Appendix L Transportation Improvements Report, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 16)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement Appendix M, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 17)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement Appendix N, 1979 November 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 18)
  - The Pine Bush Intermiunicipal Study Technical Report, 1980 January (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 19)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation - Preliminary Determination on the Proposed Crossgates, Shopping Center, 1980 March 7 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 20)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation - Preliminary Determination on Air Quality, Availability for Review, and Supplemental Notice of Hearing, 1980 March 13 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 21)
  - Applicant's response, with enclosures:, 1981 January 20; 1981 February 4; 1981 February 6; 1981 February 9 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 22-23)
  - Reapplication; Drawing B-2, 1981 July 7; 1981 July 14 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 24)
  - Traffic information, 1981 July 29; 1981 August 7 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 25)
  - New York State Department of Transportation - Record of Division, 1982 November 5 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 26)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation Certification of Roadway Design and Air Quality Analysis (with traffic plans), 1982 November 10 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 27)
  - Maps Projected. Growth Areas and Proposed Developments - Town of Guilderland, 1979 January (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 28)
  - Maps - Existing Topography (T-1), Undated (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 29)
  - Maps - Existing Land Uses and Hydrological Classification (D-2); Revised 10/17/79, 1979 May 30; 1979 October 17 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 30)
  - Maps - Profiles (D-4); Revised 10-17-79, 1979 May 30; 1979 October 17 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 31)
  - Maps - Drainage Area: (D-1) Before development - 5-30-79; Revised 10/17/79-, (D-3) After development 5-30-79; Revised 10/17/79, 1979 May 30; 1979 October 17 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 32)
  - Maps - Highway Improvement Plan (H-1A), 1979 April 19 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 33)
  - Maps - Overall Hwy. Improvement Plan (HP-A), 1979 October 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 34)
  - Maps - U. S. Route 20 Highway Improvement Plan (HP-B), 1979 October 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 35)
  - Maps - Washington Ave. Extension and Fuller Rd./I-90 Ramps Highway Improvement Plan (HP-C), 1979 October 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 36)
  - Maps - Overall Conceptual Highway Improvement Plan (HP-D), 1982 September 16 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 37)
  - Maps - Landscape Plan (L-1), 1979 May 30 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 38)
  - Maps - Layout Plan (SP-1); Revised 10-17-79, 1979 May 30; 1979 October 17 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 39)
  - Maps - Sedimentation and Erosion Cont-rol Plan (SP-4), 1979 May 30 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 40)
  - Maps - Utilities Plan (SP-3); Revised 10/17/79, 1979 May 30; 1979 October 17 (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 41)
  - Photographs and drawings, Undated (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 42)
  - News Clippings, Undated (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 1 (1-Printed Material), Folder 44)
- Stenographic Record for the State of New York Department of Environmental Conservation, 1979-1980; 2; 4.33 cubic ft.
  This series is the transcript of proceedings at public hearings. Page numbering is consecutive for the entire record.
  - Stenographic Record - Pre-Fearing Conference (pp. 1-110), 1979 August 10 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 1)
  - Stenographic Record (pp. 111-224), 1979 August 13 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 2)
  - Stenographic (pp. 225-380), 1979 December 14 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 3-4)
  - Stenographic (pp. 545-771), 1980 February 19 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 5)
  - Stenographic (pp. 772-1035), 1980 February 20 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 6)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1036-1325), 1980 February 21 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 7)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1326-1667), 1980 February 22 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 8)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1668-1779), 1980 February 22 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 9)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1780-1880), 1980 February 25 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 10)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1881-2154), 1980 February 26 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 11)
  - Stenographic (pp. 2155-2367), 1980 February 27 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 12)
  - Stenographic (pp. 2368--2561), 1980 February 28 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 13)
  - Stenographic (pp. 2562-2775), 1980 March 4 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 14)
  - Stenographic (pp. 2776-2998), 1980 March 5 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 15)
  - Stenographic (pp. 2999-3197), 1980 March 6 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 16)
  - Stenographic (pp. 3198-3460), 1980 March 7 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 17)
  - Stenographic (pp. 3461-3586), 1980 March 10 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 18)
  - Stenographic (pp. 3587-3661), 1980 March 10 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 19)
  - Stenographic (pp. 3662-3994), 1980 March 11 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 20)
  - Stenographic (pp. 3895-4124), 1980 March 12 (Box 2 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 21)
  - Stenographic (pp. 4125-4418), 1980 March 13 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 1)
  - Stenographic (pp. 4419-45,89), 1980 March 31 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 2)
  - Stenographic (pp. 4590-4862), 1980 April 1 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 3)
  - Stenographic (pp. 4863-5008), 1980 April 2 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 4)
  - Stenographic (pp. 5009-5218), 1980 April 3 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 5)
  - Stenographic (pp. 5219-5474), 1980 April 7 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 6)
  - Stenographic (pp. 5475-5793), 1980 April 8 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 7)
  - Stenographic (pp. 5794-6075), 1980 April 9 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 8)
  - Stenographic (pp. 6076-6316), 1980 April 10 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 9)
  - Stenographic (pp. 6317-6513), 1980 April 14 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 10)
  - Stenographic (pp. 6514-6761), 1980 April 15 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 11)
  - Stenographic (pp. 6762-6868), 1980 April 16 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 12)
  - Stenographic (pp. 6869-7091), 1980 April 18 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 13)
  - Stenographic (pp. 7092-7311), 1980 April 21 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 14)
  - Stenographic (pp. 7312-7607), 1980 April 22 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 15)
  - Stenographic (pp. 7608-7814), 1980 April 23 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 16)
  - Stenographic (pp. 7815-8115), 1980 April 24 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 17)
  - Stenographic (pp. 8116-8342), 1980 April 28 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 18)
  - Stenographic (pp. 8343-8533), 1980 April 29 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 19)
  - Stenographic (pp. 8534-8764), 1980 May 1 (Box 3 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 20)
  - Stenographic (pp. 8765-8922), 1980 May 2 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 1)
  - Stenographic (pp. 8923-9152), 1980 May 5 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 2)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9153-9425), 1980 May 6 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 3)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9426-9552), 1980 May 7 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 4)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9553, 1980 May 12 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 5)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9719-9879), 1980 May 13 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 6)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9880-9990), 1980 May 13 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 7)
  - Stenographic (pp. 9991-lO55), 1980 May 14 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 8)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10056-10230), 1980 May 15 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 9)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10231-10389), 1980 May 19 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 10)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10390-10556), 1980 May 20 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 11)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10557-10742), 1980 May 21 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 12)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10743-10911), 1980 May 22 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 13)
  - Stenographic (pp. 10912-11083), 1980 May 27 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 14)
  - Stenographic (pp. 11084-11253), 1980 May 28 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 15)
  - Stenographic (pp. 11254-1139,6), 1980 May 29 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 16)
  - Stenographic (pp. 11397-11633), 1980 May 30 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 17)
  - Stenographic (pp. 11634-11869), 1980 June 2 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 18)
  - Stenographic (pp. 11&70-12027), 1980 June 3 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 19)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12028-12244), 1980 June 4 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 20)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12245-12400), 1980 June 5 (Box 4 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 21)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12401-12547), 1980 June 9 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 1)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12548-12707), 1980 June 10 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 2)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12708-12850), 1980 June 12 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 3)
  - Stenographic (pp. 12851-13085), 1980 June l2 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 4)
  - Stenographic (pp. 13086-13272), 1980 June 16 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 5)
  - Stenographic (pp. 13273-13425), 1980 June 17 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 6)
  - Stenographic (pp. 13426-13651), 1980 June 18 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 7)
  - Stenographic (pp. 13652-13828), 1980 June 19 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 8)
  - Stenographic (pp. 1~829-14013), 1980 June 23 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 9)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14014-14121), 1980 June 24 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 10)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14122-14246), 1980 June 24 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 11)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14247-14412), 1980 June 25 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 12)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14413-14598), 1980 July 1 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 13)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14599-14789), 1980 July 2 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 14)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14790-14938), 1980 July 17 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 15)
  - Stenographic (pp. 14939-15154), (no pp. 15155-56), 1980 July 8 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 16)
  - Stenographic (pp. 15157-15335), (no pp. 15336-40), 1980 July 9 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 17)
  - Stenographic (pp. 15341-15531), 1980 July 10 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 18)
  - Stenographic (pp. 15532-15755), 1980 July 11 (Box 5 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 19)
  - Stenographic (pp. 15756-15908), 1980 July 14 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 1)
  - Stenographic (pp. 15909-16132), 1980 July 15 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 2-3)
  - Stenographic (pp. 16160-16246), 1980 July 16 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 4)
  - Stenographic (pp. 16247-16387), 1980 July 17 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 5)
  - Stenographic (pp. 16388-16657A), 1980 July 21 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 6)
  - Stenographic (pp. 16658-16894), 1980 July 22 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 7)
  - Stenographic (pp. 16895-17105), 1980 July 23 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 8)
  - Stenographic (pp. 17106-17216), 1980 July 24 (Box 6 (2-Stenographic Record for the State of New York Depa), Folder 9)